<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="ext_idle_notify_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2015 Martin Gräßlin
    Copyright © 2022 Simon Ser

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="ext_idle_notifier_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="get notified about user idle status">
      This interface allows clients to monitor user idle status.

      After binding the client will receive the current idle status immediately.
      Future idle status changes will be sent as events.

      Warning! The protocol described in this file is currently in the testing
      phase. Backward compatible changes may be added together with the
      corresponding interface version bump. Backward incompatible changes can
      only be done by creating a new major version of the extension.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the manager object">
        Destroy the manager object. All objects created via this interface
        remain valid.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="get_idle_notification">
      <description summary="create a notification object">
        Create a new idle notification object.

        The notification object has a minimum timeout duration and is tied to a
        seat. The client will be notified if the seat is inactive for at least
        the provided timeout. See ext_idle_notification_v1 for more details.

        A zero timeout is invalid and must result in a protocol error.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="ext_idle_notification_v1"/>
      <arg name="timeout" type="uint" summary="minimum idle timeout in msec"/>
      <arg name="seat" type="object" interface="wl_seat"/>
    </request>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="invalid_timeout" value="0"
             summary="the timeout is invalid"/>
    </enum>
  </interface>

  <interface name="ext_idle_notification_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="get notified about user idle status">
      This interface is used by the compositor to send idle notification events
      to clients.

      Initially the notification object is not idle. The notification object
      becomes idle when the associated seat has not received any user activity
      for at least the timeout, starting from the time the
      get_idle_notification request was received.

      Notification objects do not immediately become not-idle just because user
      activity was received. Instead, an idled notification is sent when the
      seat has been idle, and a resumed notification is sent when the seat
      becomes not idle again after being idle.

      The compositor must send a resumed event before the first idled event.
      Compositors may choose when to send the resumed event.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the notification object">
        Destroy the notification object.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="idled">
      <description summary="notification object is idle">
        This event is sent when the notification object becomes idle.

        It's a compositor error to send this event twice without a resumed
        event in between.
      </description>
    </event>

    <event name="resumed">
      <description summary="notification object is not idle">
        This event is sent when the notification object is no longer idle.

        It's a compositor error to send this event twice without an idled
        event in between. The first resumed event may be sent at any time
        after the notification object is created.
      </description>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
